Ben Scott

Data visualization, infographics, journalist





(985) 246-4675

www.benpedroscott.com

Profile

I'm a budding data journalist with newsroom experience at the **University of Missouri**. I'm learning JavaScript and D3 in an independent study this semester.

Software

Adobe Illustrator InDesign, Photoshop Tableau, Datawrapper WordPress, BLOX CMS iNews, MediaCentral

Computer Languages

HTML, CSS Learning JavaScript and D3 Vega-Lite API DB Browser, SQL-lite

Soft Skills

Graphic design Copy editing, AP Style Data analysis, news reporting Remote work

Education

University of Missouri-Columbia Data journalism major **English** minor Honors college - 3.7 GPA Graduation December 2021

Experience

Columbia Missourian Graphics Editor (January 2021 to present)

- Teaching assistant for the graphics desk and infographics class for a newspaper serving mid-Missouri region.
- Teach new graphics reporters how to use Adobe Illustrator to create infographics and data viz for print and digital.
- Participate in daily budget meetings with faculty editors in planning upcoming content.

MSNBC Breaking News Intern (summer 2021)

- Logged and transcribed interviews on major TV networks.
- Monitored social media and local news outlets for any breaking storylines report, such as the Surfside building collapse.
- Watched press conferences and chose best quotes to transcribe, developing a keen news sense.

Columbia Missourian Staffer (May 2020 to present)

- Assumed various roles, currently work as a copy editor.
- Daily reporter in summer 2020. Covered COVID-19 beat along with general assignments and mastered basics of journalism.
- Graphics reporter in fall 2020, Learned how to visualize quantities in a contextual and simple manner.

Maneater Student Politics Editor (April 2019 to May 2020)

Managed section of around 10 student reporters at Mizzou's independent student newspaper and edited their stories.

Maneater Staff Writer (September 2018 to April 2019)

Pitched and wrote weekly stories for student politics section.

Chipotle Employee (August 2018 to January 2020)